LA'TONIA MERTICA SHEPPARD WALKER

writer | photographer { full stack engineer } videographer | designer

2200 S Salina St #684 Syracuse NY 13205 | 315.987.1687 | latoniamertica@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/latoniamertica

SUMMARY

Full Stack Javascript Engineer with specialization in Python and design. Proficient in CSS, HTML, Javascript, Django, React, databases, Sequelize, SQL, Node, ORM, OOP, Git, and Github. Marketing/Design genius turned engineer proficient in Adobe Suite Indesign, Photoshop, Premiere Pro, and creatives skills that include conceptualization and deliverables.

EXPERIENCE

Founder & Executive Officer

La'Tonia Mertica 'Communications & Creatives Specialist'

09/2019 - present

- Brand, voice, and identity establishment, fine tuning, and evolution
- Content generation and curation (ie. stock pix/vix; graphic design)
- Social media setup and temporary management, including tech skills building
- Landing page development and landing/home page redevelopment
- Efficiency consultation for elevated content reuse, editing, and/or repurposing
- Holistic B2B communication services for heightened small business presence online and off

Communications Manager

CenterState CEO Syracuse Surge - aka The Surge

09/2021 - 02/2022

- High-profile partner collaboration to co-plan, implement, and execute strategic communications
- Partner/Contractor management to generate content, produce deliverables, and deploy earned media
- Tactical communications implementation to build the local tech eco system via untapped talent

Marketing Team Intern

Full Bodied Health 'Nutrition for The Health You Deserve'

11/2020 - 01/2021

- Idea and strategy implementation to enhance brand and increase awareness/engagement
- Website/Landing page creation, dressing, and redevelopment with pre-existing collaterals
- Social media content generation and curation, re-purposing, and administrative strategy
- General consultation to better inform strategic implementation of creatives and marketing

EDUCATION

Emergent Works

formerly Code Cooperative

• Javascript 1:1 Mentorship

Columbia University

Justice Through Code

• Full Stack Python Bootcamp

Hack Upstate

Careers in Code

• Full Stack Javascript Bootcamp

Brooklyn, New York 11/2021 - present

New York, New York 08/2021 - 02/2022

Syracuse, New York 03/2021 - 08/2021

